<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on My Blog</title>
        <link>https://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on My Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-in</language>
        <copyright>All Rights Reserved</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 20:29:31 +0530</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="rss://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Blog 1: Rethinking Coalignment from Ground-up</title>
            <link>https://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/blog_1/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 20:29:31 +0530</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/blog_1/</guid>
            <description>The Very Essence of Coalignment At its core, coalignment is all about making sure our solar images match up as best they can. It uses a few different techniques, like template matching and solar rotation correction, to get this done. This is really important when we&amp;rsquo;re trying to accurately track and study what&amp;rsquo;s happening on a part of sun over time. We re-thought the entire process of what our new API be providing to the users as well as its structure.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-very-essence-of-coalignment">The Very Essence of Coalignment</h2>
<p>At its core, coalignment is all about making sure our solar images match up as best they can. It uses a few different techniques, like template matching and solar rotation correction, to get this done. This is really important when we&rsquo;re trying to accurately track and study what&rsquo;s happening on a part of sun over time.
We re-thought the entire process of what our new API be providing to the users as well as its structure.</p>
<p><img alt="Naive Refactor" src="/images/proposed_struct.png"></p>
<p>This was one of the idea that was very naive version, but focused entierly for the user&rsquo;s comfort in applying the coalignment methods.</p>
<h2 id="the-basic-structure-we-finally-agreed-upon">The Basic Structure we finally agreed Upon</h2>
<p><img alt="Internal Sturcture" src="/images/internal.png"></p>
<p>We agreed to have this as the very basic structure which we would be working/developing upwards. The following example demonstrates the way it would work.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span style="display:flex;"><span>aia_map1 <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> sunpy<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>map<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>Map(sunpy<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>data<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>sample<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>AIA_193_CUTOUT01_IMAGE)
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>aia_map2 <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> sunpy<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>map<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>Map(sunpy<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>data<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>sample<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>AIA_193_CUTOUT03_IMAGE)
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#75715e">### Creating a template from aia_map1</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>bottom_left <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> SkyCoord(<span style="color:#ae81ff">600</span> <span style="color:#f92672">*</span> u<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>arcsec, <span style="color:#f92672">-</span><span style="color:#ae81ff">500</span> <span style="color:#f92672">*</span> u<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>arcsec, frame<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>aia_map1<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>coordinate_frame)
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>top_right <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> SkyCoord(<span style="color:#ae81ff">800</span> <span style="color:#f92672">*</span> u<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>arcsec, <span style="color:#f92672">-</span><span style="color:#ae81ff">200</span> <span style="color:#f92672">*</span> u<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>arcsec, frame<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>aia_map1<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>coordinate_frame)
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>submap <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> aia_map1<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>submap(bottom_left, top_right<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>top_right)
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>coaligned_map <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> coalignment_interface(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;match_template&#34;</span>,aia_map2, submap)
</span></span></code></pre></div><p><img alt="combined image" src="/images/combined.png"></p>
<p>I am currently implementing the decorator structure for the sunkit-image, but that would be covered in another blog.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Journey to Google Summer of Code 2024</title>
            <link>https://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/journey/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 20:29:31 +0530</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/journey/</guid>
            <description>Hey Jayraj, What&amp;rsquo;s your story about getting into GSoC? One of the most repeatedly asked question since the contributor results got announced by Google. All right peeps, lets do this one last time ;)
What is GSoC you say? Well, Google Summer of Code (GSoC) is a global program focused on bringing more student developers into open source software development. Students work with an open-source organization on a 12+ week programming project during summer.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h5 id="hey-jayraj-whats-your-story-about-getting-into-gsoc"><em>Hey Jayraj, What&rsquo;s your story about getting into GSoC?</em></h5>
<p>One of the most repeatedly asked question since the contributor results got announced by Google. All right peeps, lets do this one last time ;)</p>
<h2 id="what-is-gsoc-you-say-well">What is GSoC you say? Well,</h2>
<p><img alt="GSoC" src="/images/gsocxsunpy.png"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Google Summer of Code (GSoC) is a global program focused on bringing more student developers into open source software development. Students work with an open-source organization on a 12+ week programming project during summer.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Personally, I think this is one of the best programs Google runs. It gives talented individuals an amazing incentive to dive into open-source contributions and make a real impact.</p>
<p>What&rsquo;s even cooler is that most participants continue contributing to open-source long after the program ends because they genuinely fall in love with it.
<em><strong>GSoC doesn&rsquo;t just build skills; it builds a lasting community of passionate developers.</strong></em></p>
<h2 id="discovering-gsoc">Discovering GSoC</h2>
<p>My journey into GSoC began with a spark of inspiration from a senior at IIT Gandhinagar, who had been building the tech community in our institute, inspired me through his extremely cool contributions and ideas. I still remember vividly our discussions over building tech culture, venting about dean, SA office.</p>
<p>One night, in the middle of one of these classic rants, my curiosity got the better of me. I asked him about his GSoC journey. What followed was an hour of riveting stories about his contributions and experiences. His tales were so exciting that they lit a fire in me.</p>
<p>That conversation was my nudge to dive into the world of open source and try to contribute something cool and meaningful. And thus, my GSoC adventure began.</p>
<h2 id="choosing-an-organization">Choosing an Organization</h2>
<p>Next up was the big decision: choosing which organization to work with for GSoC. This wasn’t just a quick pick; it was all about aligning my interests with the impact I wanted to make. I dove into exploring various organizations and their projects, trying to match them with my current skill set.</p>
<p>To get a real feel for what each organization was about, I rolled up my sleeves and tried out different projects firsthand. I dabbled in cybersecurity, web development, and everything else that piqued my interest. It was all about finding that perfect fit where I could contribute meaningfully and learn a ton.</p>
<h2 id="contributing-to-open-source">Contributing to Open-Source</h2>
<p>I started contributing to open-source projects right when Hacktoberfest was starting, trying out different projects like OWASP-BLT, Plone. The initial days were challenging, filled with learning curves and difficulties. However, these experiences were invaluable in building my skills and confidence. Here mainly my Google-fu skills came into help to fix few good-first-issues. I kept on solving an issue after another.</p>
<p>After a few months into contributing, I wasn&rsquo;t intimated by the size of the codebase, it was all a matter of time that I could dedicate to get into the depths of an issue and the relevant documenation/concepts. After that what left was just <strong>plain ol&rsquo; implementation</strong>.</p>
<h2 id="first-experience-with-sunpy">First Experience with SunPy</h2>
<p>While exploring different projects, I stumbled upon OpenAstronomy, an umbrella organization focused on astrophysics. I was immediately drawn to the stunning example galleries of SunPy and sunkit-image. SunPy is a community dedicated to solar physics, and their work was nothing short of mesmerizing. At this point, I was all about challenging myself with tough projects that stretched my expertise.</p>
<p>The SunPy community was amazing—full of brilliant yet humble individuals whose insightful and humorous discussions about mind-boggling topics resonated deeply with my inner astronaut. I was fascinated by the significant impact of their work on the world. That&rsquo;s when I knew I had found the organization I was eager to contribute to.</p>
<h2 id="proposal-and-my-chosen-project">Proposal and My Chosen Project</h2>
<p>I chose the sunkit-image project because it had plenty of issues that needed attention, and at its core, it&rsquo;s an image processing library—one of my favorite skills. Writing the proposal was a meticulous process that required clarity, precision, and a strong understanding of the project goals. I started by drafting the basic structure and changes needed to make the package more useful and active again. The challenge of keeping the proposal within the 5-page limit made it even more interesting, as I had to include only the most important parts and link all the code in GitHub gists.</p>
<p>I had some great discussions with mentors and the SunPy community, and based on their feedback, I made several improvements to my proposal. I also addressed numerous queries to ensure everything was clear and thorough.</p>
<h2 id="announcement-day">Announcement Day</h2>
<p>The day the results were announced was unforgettable. I had just finished my final exams that evening and was out with my friends, unwinding after all the stress. Suddenly, <em>ding</em>, a notification popped up that made my night and turned the last six months into something truly memorable.
<img alt="Yay!" src="/images/selected.png"></p>
<p>All the hard work, perseverance, and dedication had finally paid off—I had been officially selected for GSoC 2024. It marked the beginning of an exciting new chapter in my journey.</p>
<p>My journey to GSoC 2024 has been a rollercoaster of emotions and learning experiences. It has taught me the value of persistence, the importance of community, and the joy of contributing to something bigger than myself. I hope my story inspires you to embark on your own journey and make a meaningful impact.</p>
<hr>
<p>Thank you for joining me on this journey. Stay tuned for more updates as I continue to explore and contribute to the world of open source.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Blog 0: The First Two Weeks</title>
            <link>https://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/blog_0/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 20:29:31 +0530</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/blog_0/</guid>
            <description>A summary of activities completed in the two weeks leading up to the start of the coding period. Table of Contents Wrapping up the draft pull request Incorporating suggestions for STARA &amp;amp; its examples Fixing the doc failures First Meet with Mentors After completing my end-semester exams, I was overwhelmed by the outstanding tasks that I had let accumulate over time. In order to address those, I tried resolving dependencies and package issues of the previous environments of sunpy &amp;amp; sunkit-image but, ultimately gave up and initialised a new environment.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="a-summary-of-activities-completed-in-the-two-weeks-leading-up-to-the-start-of-the-coding-period">A summary of activities completed in the two weeks leading up to the start of the coding period.</h4>
<h2 id="table-of-contents">Table of Contents</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="/posts/blog_0/#draft_pr">Wrapping up the draft pull request</a></li>
<li><a href="/posts/blog_0/#issue1">Incorporating suggestions for STARA &amp; its examples</a></li>
<li><a href="/posts/blog_0/#fix_doc_fails">Fixing the doc failures</a></li>
<li><a href="/posts/blog_0/#first_meet">First Meet with Mentors</a></li>
</ul>
<p>After completing my end-semester exams, I was overwhelmed by the outstanding tasks that I had let accumulate over time.
In order to address those, I tried resolving dependencies and package issues of the previous environments of
sunpy &amp; sunkit-image but, ultimately gave up and initialised a new environment. After discussions with mentors, the project priorities were clarified, allowing me to efficiently plan &amp; complete my tasks during the community bonding period. What follows is the detailed account of all the tasks completed during these two weeks.</p>
<h2 id="incorporating-suggestions-for-sunspot-tracking-and-recognition-algorithm-stara">Incorporating suggestions for Sunspot Tracking and Recognition Algorithm (STARA)</h2>
<p>Incorporated suggestions and made several changes to the STARA example. Attempted to create a mock HMI continuum data with an artificial &ldquo;sunspot&rdquo; at a chosen location with a certain radius. But it did not meet the exact requirements of the STARA, hence no regions could be identified. The written mock hmi map are demonstrated below,</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center"><img alt="Mock HMI Map without Sunspot" src="/images/mock_wo.png"></th>
<th style="text-align:center"><img alt="Mock HMI Map with Sunspot" src="/images/mock_withspot.png"></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">Mock HMI Map without Sunspot</td>
<td style="text-align:center">Mock HMI Map with Sunspot</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Discussed alternative approaches with mentor Nabil regarding the mock HMI map. According to his suggestion I tried the HMI continuum test data present in <code>sunpy/data/test</code> directory, but it had some issues with the WCS hence STARA couldn&rsquo;t properly find the sunspot regions.</p>
<h2 id="wrapping-up-the-draft-pull-request">Wrapping up the draft pull request</h2>
<p>I began working on the transformation of a vector field some time ago but encountered challenges in validating the approach. Using Astropy for the transformation confirmed the accuracy of the function I wrote. The next step is to seek feedback from mentors and the SunPy community. But I still feel a need to test this more rigorously which can validate that this would work with different frames too. I studied about different frames provided by the SPICE toolkit and tried to match the sunpy frames and the SPICE frames and have confirmed that the function works with the static frames.</p>
<h2 id="fixing-the-doc-failures">Fixing the doc failures</h2>
<p>Two out of my three open pull requests encountered documentation failures due to incorrect referencing of functions or modules, or example galleries. After studying the conventions of Sphinx and SunPy, I resolved these issues. Additionally, I discovered how to set up GitHub CI actions on my forks.</p>
<h2 id="first-meet-with-mentors">First Meet with Mentors</h2>
<p>In our initial meeting, my mentor Will provided a brief overview of the purpose of sunkit-image, emphasizing its primary function: coalignment. He explained the fundamental concepts of coalignment, user expectations, and desired functionalities of the new API. We also reviewed the current coalignment API&rsquo;s shortcomings. We agreed that an improved API was necessary and discussed my proposed structure for this enhancement. We also drafted a plan for the entire rethinking and redesigning the new API over the span of 4 weeks.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
