<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Blog</title>
    <link>https://deus1704.vercel.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-in</language>
    <copyright>All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 17:29:31 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="rss://deus1704.vercel.app/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blog 3: Side Quests Week</title>
      <link>https://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/blog_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 17:29:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/blog_3/</guid>
      <description>While the mentors are waiting for community reviews on the new coalignment API, I&amp;rsquo;ve been diving into some fun side quests.&#xA;Side Quest 1: ASDA Example The long-needed Automated Swirl Detection Algorithm (ASDA) example gallery in the sunkit-image is now ready. The ASDA module is for identifying the swirls or vortices in the 2D flow field of the solar atmosphere. ASDA offers a robust tool for detecting and analyzing the vortices in the solar atmosphere.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog 2: All Pieces Falling into place</title>
      <link>https://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/blog_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 16:29:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/blog_2/</guid>
      <description>Update On New Coalignment The very first version of the new Coalignment API has been completely implemented, with all the test cases written! The architecture of the proposed co-alignment API closely mirrors the design principles found in SunPy&amp;rsquo;s rotation module, where a decorator pattern is employed to register specific methods designated for executing co-alignment tasks. Detailed documentation and guidelines on utilizing the new API are available for review at this docs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog 1: Rethinking Coalignment from Ground-up</title>
      <link>https://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/blog_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 20:29:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/blog_1/</guid>
      <description>The Very Essence of Coalignment At its core, coalignment is all about making sure our solar images match up as best they can. It uses a few different techniques, like template matching and solar rotation correction, to get this done. This is really important when we&amp;rsquo;re trying to accurately track and study what&amp;rsquo;s happening on a part of sun over time. We re-thought the entire process of what our new API be providing to the users as well as its structure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Journey to Google Summer of Code 2024</title>
      <link>https://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 20:29:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/journey/</guid>
      <description>Hey Jayraj, What&amp;rsquo;s your story about getting into GSoC? One of the most repeatedly asked question since the contributor results got announced by Google. All right peeps, lets do this one last time ;)&#xA;What is GSoC you say? Well, Google Summer of Code (GSoC) is a global program focused on bringing more student developers into open source software development. Students work with an open-source organization on a 12+ week programming project during summer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog 0: The First Two Weeks</title>
      <link>https://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/blog_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 20:29:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deus1704.vercel.app/posts/blog_0/</guid>
      <description>A summary of activities completed in the two weeks leading up to the start of the coding period. Table of Contents Wrapping up the draft pull request Incorporating suggestions for STARA &amp;amp; its examples Fixing the doc failures First Meet with Mentors After completing my end-semester exams, I was overwhelmed by the outstanding tasks that I had let accumulate over time. In order to address those, I tried resolving dependencies and package issues of the previous environments of sunpy &amp;amp; sunkit-image but, ultimately gave up and initialised a new environment.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
